A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), Office Files of John P. Santos FA540
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject and chronological files, 1986-2002; 1; 10.77 Cubic Feet About 24 LTR size Hollinger boxes, 3 LGL size Hollinger boxes, and 1 Half-LGL size Hollinger box
  - Harvard University John F. Kennedy School of Government - Clarifying the CNN Effect, 1997 June (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - New York Times - Reviving the Tired Image of the 'Latin Other', 1998 January 4 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Gigi B. Sohn - Media Access Project, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Independents convening - Independent Producers' Roundtable, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Digital Television in an Era of "Radical Instability" by David Rosen - Presentation, undated (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - Independents convening - Independent Producers' Roundtable minutes, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 194)
  - Civil society media, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 195)
  - Martinez, Armando - A Comment on the Zapatista "Netwar", 1997 May 15 (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - African-American Institute (AAI) Roundtable - Connecting Worlds: Africa and the United States in the Information Age, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - Sithengi: Annual Southern African International Film and Television Market at Cape Town, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - University of Georgia College of Journalism Peabody Awards, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - Cuba, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - American Demographics - Watching in Tongues, 1998 April (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Center for Media Education, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - The Orient Foundation - Strategies for the Creation of Multimedia Archival Libraries, 1996-1998 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Coumba Lamba, USA: An African Traditional Healing Ceremony Held in Gathering with Native Americans, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - American Documentary, Inc. - The Television Race Initiative, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 205)
    File also contains a set of documents regarding the People's Poetry Gathering.
  - National Black Programming Consortium (NBPC), 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Deep Dish TV Network, 1986-1998 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1989-1997 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA) delegation, 1997; File contains an audio cassette titled United States Information Agency (USIA)/Princeton Summer Seminar Meeting at Ford (tape 1 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 209-210)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA)/Princeton Summer Seminar Meeting at Ford, 1997 August 7; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 9445)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - TV crime coverage, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Videazimut, 1997 April (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - West Glen, 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - WGBH donor-lists issue, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Wireless report - The Council of Economic Advisers, 2000 October (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Wolf, Naomi - The Woodhull Institute for Ethical Leadership, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - WNYC Radio - On the Media (OTM), 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - WYNC Radio - September 11 attacks 1 million dollar grant, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - World Media Foundation, Inc., 2000 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - WITNESS - General correspondence, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - WNET, 1992-2002 (Box 16, Folder 222-223)
  - WNET, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - WBEZ Alliance, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation, 1998-2002 (Box 16, Folder 226-227)
  - William Greaves Productions, 1999-2001 (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - Yeshiva University, 1998-2000 (Box 17, Folder 229-231)
  - American Academy in Berlin, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Bay of Pigs - USA Today article, 1997 June 23 (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Benton Foundation, 1997-2001 (Box 17, Folder 234-236)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting - Ford Foundation Program in Mexico and Central America, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 237)
  - Brown University - Report of the Visiting Committee on Diversity, 1999-2001 (Box 18, Folder 238-239)
  - Bay Area Video Coalition (BAVC) - Information and Communications Technology (ICT) workshop, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 240-241)
  - Camino de las Culturas, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 242)
  - Center for Media Education (CME), 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 243-244)
  - Center for Public Integrity, 1993-2000 (Box 19, Folder 245-246)
  - Slavin/Schaffer films and WNET-New York - Americans, undated (Box 19, Folder 247)
  - Smithsonian Center for Latino initiatives, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 248)
  - Program Officer orientation, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 249-250)
  - Council on Foundations 2000 Annual Conference Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 251-252)
  - Ford Foundation Worldwide Development Finance Meeting, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - Rizvi, Gowher 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 254-255)
  - Romero, Anthony 1999 Fiscal Year (Box 20, Folder 256)
  - Romero, Anthony 1999 Fiscal Year - Antonia Pantoja Book Project, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 257)
  - Romero, Anthony 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 258)
  - Smith, Marcia 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 259)
  - Siskel, Suzanne 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 260)
  - Telles, Edward 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 261)
  - Vincent, Christine 1999 Fiscal Year, 1991-1999 (Box 20, Folder 262-263)
  - Wilkerson, Margaret 1999 Fiscal Year, 1995-1999 (Box 20, Folder 264)
  - Wilde, Alexander 1999 Fiscal Year, 1996-1999 (Box 20, Folder 265)
  - Wilson, Ken 1999 Fiscal Year, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 266)
  - Wing, Christine 1999 Fiscal Year - Kosovo Working Group (Box 20, Folder 267)
  - Wing, Christine 1999 Fiscal Year, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 268)
  - Wing, Christine 1999 Fiscal Year - James Der Derian, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 269-270)
  - Anglin, Roland 1998 Fiscal Year (Box 21, Folder 271)
  - Batliwala, Srilatha 1998 Fiscal Year - Fund for New Performance/Video and CIVICUS: World Alliance for Civic Participation, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 272)
  - Ellis Island 1998 Fiscal Year, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 273)
  - Funabiki, Jon 1998 Fiscal Year- New York University, Eileen Willis, 1997 November 20 (Box 21, Folder 274)
  - Funabiki, Jon 1998 Fiscal Year, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 275)
  - Ispahani, Mahnaz 1998 Fiscal Year (Box 21, Folder 276)
  - Jenkins, Alan 1998 Fiscal Year- Black Leadership Forum (BLF), 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 277)
  - Jenkins, Alan 1998 Fiscal Year - Black Feminism (Box 21, Folder 278)
  - Lipski, Michael 1998 Fiscal Year - Ginzberg Video, Generation Hope (Box 21, Folder 279)
  - Mensah, Lisa 1998 Fiscal Year, 1989-1998 (Box 21, Folder 280)
  - Misra, Greeta 1998 Fiscal Year, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 281)
  - Misra, Greeta 1998 Fiscal Year, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 282)
  - Mohamed, Inca A. 1998 Fiscal Year (Box 21, Folder 283)
  - Neuborne, Helen 1998 Fiscal Year - Union Institute Center for Women (Box 22, Folder 284)
  - Neuborne, Helen 1998 Fiscal Year, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 285)
  - Odaga, Adhiambo 1998 Fiscal Year - World Wildlife Federation (WWF) (Box 22, Folder 286)
  - Overseas 1998 Fiscal Year, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 287-288)
  - Petrovich, Janice 1998 Fiscal Year - Adult Literacy Media Alliance (ALMA), 1997-1998 (Box 22, Folder 289-290)
  - Ramanathan, Sharada 1998 Fiscal Year - Center for the Study of Culture and Society (Box 22, Folder 291)
  - Ramanathan, Sharada 1998 Fiscal Year, 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 292-293)
  - Tomas Rivera Policy Institute (TRPI), 1996-1999 (Box 23, Folder 294-295)
  - Santucho, Julio, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 296)
  - Russia, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 297)
  - Santos photograph, 2000; File contains a still image. The image is of John Phillip Santos. It was taken during a visit Santos made to California in 2000. (Box 23, Folder 298)
  - Council on Foundations 2000-2001 Film and Video Festival, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 299-300)
  - International Design Conference in Aspen (IDCA), 2000-2001 (Box 23, Folder 301)
  - Council on Foundations 2000-2001 Film and Video Festival, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 302)
  - Fiscal Year 2000 Fourth Quarter Meeting, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 303)
  - Fiscal Year 2000 First Quarter Meeting, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 304)
  - Digital grantees meeting - Rooming list, etc., circa 2000 (Box 23, Folder 305)
    File pertains to the Convening of Public Television Grantees hosted at the Ford Foundation in November 2000. The grantee organizations that participated in the meeting were part of the Digital Public Television Initiative.
  - Digital grantees meeting - Handouts, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 306)
  - Digital grantees meeting - Hotel, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 307)
  - Digital grantees meeting - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 308)
  - Digital grantees meeting - Agenda and invitees, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 309)
  - Digital grantees meeting - Restaurant, 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 310)
  - Bay Area Video Coalition (BVAC) - CEF support for stakeholders meeting, 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 311-312)
  - Service/Business Models Project presentation, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 313-314)
  - Native American Public Telecommunications (NAPT), 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 315)
  - Convening of Public Broadcasting Grantees, 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 316)
  - Chronological file, 2000-2001 (Box 25, Folder 317-319)
  - Chronological file, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 320-322)
    Original folder label said that this chronological file was for April to September 2000, but file actually contains documents from 1999 and other months in 2000.
  - PBS, 2000-2001 (Box 25, Folder 323)
  - PBS - Pat Mitchell, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 324)
  - PBS, 1993-2001 (Box 26, Folder 325-326)
  - Program Associate - Hardy, Karin, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 327)
  - Public Radio Capital Fund, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 328)
  - People - Camerini Robertson, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 329)
  - People - Davis, Dee, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 330)
  - People - Etheredge, Lloyd, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 331)
  - People - Else, Jon, 2002 January (Box 26, Folder 332)
  - People - Friedman, Thomas, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 333)
  - People - Itkoff, Sandy, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 334)
  - One World International Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 26, Folder 335)
  - One World International Foundation - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 336)
  - The Panos Institute, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 337)
  - Pacifica Foundation, 1997-2001 (Box 26, Folder 338)
  - Public Radio International, 1996-2001 (Box 26, Folder 339-340)
  - Public Service Broadcasting Trust (PSBT), 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 341-342)
  - Radio Diaries, 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 343)
  - Roundtable, Inc., 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 344-345)
  - Radio Exchange, undated (Box 27, Folder 346)
  - Rhizome, 1999-2001 (Box 27, Folder 347)
  - San Francisco State University, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 348)
  - Songmasters, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 349)
    File contains a group of records that may have belonged to a different file at one point or that may have been intended to be placed in a different file. These records regard a collaboration between the Center for Media and Learning (CML)/American Social History Project (ASHP) at City University of New York (CUNY) and Clarity Film Productions.
  - University of Southern California, 1988-2000 (Box 28, Folder 350-353)